# **Blake James**

Lexington, KY 40509 | bjames.56@icloud.com | (606)-273-4589

#### Summary

A self-starting tech-professional that constantly formulates, refines, and implements ways to simplify and optimize workflow. Comfortable operating independently, but thrives as part of or leading a group, having over 5 years of management experience across multiple fields. A team player who leads by example doing what is necessary to get the job done correctly.

## **Technical Skills**

Operating Systems: Windows (XP, 10, 11)

Programming languages: HTML5, CSS3, Java Script

Software Applications: Microsoft Office, Github, Visual Studio Code, Node.js, React, Express,

Mongo DB, Mongoose

#### Education

**Per Scholas** Software Engineering Cincinnati, Oh Graduation November/2022 **West Virginia University** Industrial Engineering Morgantown, Wv

Completed 90+ credits January 2014-December2014 **West Virginia University** Mechanical/Aerospace Engineering Morgantown, Wv

Completed 75+ credits August 2007- May2012

### **Professional Experience**

Wendy's | Shift supervisor | Lexington, KY | May 2018-October 2019 June 2021-Current-

- Delegate duties and supervise in their completion to ensure standards are met
- Exercise good problem-solving skills by identifying tasks to prioritize
- Utilizes technology to log inventory and manage end of day cash flow
- Design and adapt training programs to effectively teach new skills to employees
- Verify products to quickly and accurately deliver to customers

Kelly Services | Assembly worker | Georgetown, KY | October 2019 - May 2021

- Effectively communicated within small teams to increase production speed, eliminate down time and reduce defected vehicles
- Operated machinery and power tools to assemble products (vehicles) with precision and speed
- Adapted to situation and challenges on the fly to correct errors and properly fit and install parts

**Horseshoe Southern Indiana Casino** | Supervisor/ Table Games Dealer | Elizabeth, IN | June 2017- September 2017-

- Managed and tracked bankrolls for multiple tables and patrons at once
- Practiced conflict management and mediation skills to correct deviations from standard practice
- Clearly communicated with patrons to advise on best practices on course of play
- Utilized time management skills and identification of personnel strengths to best place myself to reduce losses and improve productivity

Lady Luck Casino | Table Games Dealer | Farmington PA | May 2015- April 2017

- Demonstrated showmanship and poise in public situations hosting patrons applying humor and positive engagement speaking comfortably to groups to build rapport
- Effectively communicated state and casino rules and regulations to patrons with clarity
- Practiced hand dexterity and rapid mental math computation skills to increase productivity

Sheetz | Shift Supervisor | Morgantown, WV | June2012-December2013

- Used interpersonal skills to resolve conflicts, relate to customers, and improve customer service
- Assessed situations to identify bottlenecks in real time and support those areas to improve productivity
- Communicated easily with different personalities to cooperate on projects and build rapport
- Motivated and helped guide employees in the completion of tasks and fulfillment of company goals